Andrew A Hamlin

860-810-6538 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewahamlin | aahamlin@gmail.com

Profile

A software development manager and servant leader who has delivered industry-leading software solutions recognized by Gartner and KLAS. Over 20 years hands-on experience with Agile software development and release management (Scrum/Kanban), enterprise architecture, cloud architecture, test-driven development, systems integration, CI/CD, global workforce management, and team building.

Relevant Skills

- Leadership and nurturing of highly engaged software development teams
- Stewardship and continuous improvement of processes and best practices
- Collaboration with product owners, designers, partners, and customers
- Development of fault-tolerant, distributed systems incl. web & mobile UIs

Experience

Gerber Technology, LLC: Tolland, CT

2018-2019

Sr Software Development Manager

Assessed overall release management and development processes and created improved workflows tailored to the organization's needs. Trained cross-functional team of approx. 50 people during transition from 1-yr to 3-mo release cycles

Led estimation, capacity planning, and feature delivery of 3 project teams, approx. 25 developers, working in Agile/Scrum environment

Established best practices including refactoring, design reviews, and code reviews that yielded an 86% reduction in defects over 2 major releases

Championed transparency and initiated data-driven improvements that provided predictability and shortened lead time to story acceptance by 81%

Managed 8 direct reports, 20 offshore contract resources, mentored 2 team leads

Sailpoint Technologies: Austin, TX 2017-2018

Software Development Manager

Championed and expanded best practices in code reviews, test coverage, documentation, threat modeling, CI/CD, and localization

Led delivery of frontend and backend features in Java, SQL and Angular.js

Served as scrum master of two 6-8 person scrum teams

Managed 8 direct reports. Conducted interviews. Onboarded 4 new hires

Caradigm USA, LLC: Bellevue, WA (Remote)

2012-2016

Software Development Manager & Team Lead: 2013 - 2016

Delivered two products using Agile/Scrum methodology, working collaboratively with product owners and 6-8 person scrum teams

Envisioned and led development of CI/CD pipeline, with gated-checkins and endto-end test automation, coached team members on its adoption and use

Developed interviewing and onboarding standards and documentation

Personally implemented UI, CLI, REST APIs in C#, SQL, Javascript, Python, and C

Sustaining Engineering Manager: 2012 - 2013

Established and owned prioritization process and service level agreements (SLAs) used to serve customer support, professional service and pre-sales teams Earned Employee Recognition Award for outstanding team results against SLAs

Managed 10-person on/offshore team including 8 contract resources

Microsoft Corporation: Redmond, WA (Remote)

2010-2012

Software Development Engineer II

Defined architecture and led 6-person team transforming a monolithic Java app to service-based architecture in C#/.NET, WCF, WPF, and PowerShell

Co-developed self-contained polyglot build system including static code analysis and test coverage; used by 40+ developers

Sentillion, Inc: Andover, MA

2010-2012

Senior Software Engineer

Developed Java and Perl/CGI components for enterprise IAM/SSO solution for Linux and Windows exceeding 99.999% uptime; a KLAS Top 20 product Eliminated costs by replacing high-availability (HA) solution with OSS alternative

Personal & Volunteer Activities

Unplugg Enterprises: Easthampton, MA

2019

Developed Dart/Flutter mobile application. Designed UI/UX with Adobe XD

The Master's School: West Simsbury, CT

2014-2015

Created programming elective for students. Taught 16 high school students

Education

Daniel Webster College: Nashua, NH

BS Management and Information Technology